Shivam Kumar

Software Development Engineer II

An accomplished Embedded Software Engineer with 4 years of experience in embedded software design and development. Ability to work in an agile, iterative development environment with in-depth knowledge of C, C++, Linux, Data Structures, Algorithms, IPC, RTOS, Device **Drivers** and **Serial Peripherals**.

shivamvns1995@gmail.com



(+91) 8896627159



P Bengaluru, India



in linkedin.com/in/shivam01july

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer II Infinera, Bengaluru, Karnataka

07/2020 - Present

Tasks

- Developing an application software to integrate digital protection switch for ongoing traffic in telecom system using C++.
- o Implemented an algorithm to establish end-to-end acknowledge based Synchronised Communication between APU and RPU.
- Developed a full cycle of RTC Watchdog Timer to handle all the case scenarios.
- o Implemented features in the Real-Time multi-processor domain on an RTOS system (FreeRTOS).
- Wrote optimized and performant code, and proficiently debugged and profiled multi-threaded applications.
- o Developed a lightweight application that parallelly operates in run time environment to monitor RPU Firmware health.

R&D Engineer

Tejas Networks Ltd., Bengaluru, Karnataka

09/2018 - 06/2020

- o Developed and Debugged software application for telecom products on Linux Operating Environment using C and C++.
- Performed Device Driver development for embedded control peripherals like I2C, SPI, PmBus, Flash and UART.
- Developed EEPROM and In-System programming for controller and line cards.
- o Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Developed an integrated embedded Linux interface to connect software application layers.
- · Optimized code by rewriting many modules.

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma (PG - DESD)

Center for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC - ACTS), Bengaluru

2018 Stream Grade: A

Embedded System Design

Bachelor Of Technology (B. Tech)

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

2013 - 2017

Stream

Electronics & Communication Engineering

SKILLS

Proficient in C and C++ programming

Programming and Debugging in the Linux Operating Environment

Multithread as well as Asynchronous Programming

Firmware Design with Real-Time Operating System (RTOS)

Linux Device Drivers Development

Embedded Control Peripherals - Flash, UART, I2C, PmBus and SPI

Real-Time Multi-Processor Development

Possess Knowledge of Data Structures & OS Concepts

Knowledge of Software Design Patterns & Modern **Coding Principles**

Working Experience in R&D Environment

Decisive in Taking Decisions

Complex Problem Solving Skills

ACHIEVEMENTS

- * Won 8 Robotics Competitions, organised by various Engineering Tech Societies.
- ★ Secured the ISIE Future Award in Electric Vehicle Championship (ESVC-2K17), organised by the Imperial Society of Innovative Engineers (ISIE).
- * Received Special Appreciation Award from A.K.T.U. University for making Inordinate Procure Vault (IPV) and Device for Uniquely Abled (DUA).

LANGUAGES

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Solving Rubik's Cubes

Computer Games

Playing Chess

Robotics